quiz = [
    {
        'question': 'what is the first step in the software development lifecycle ?',
        'options': ['system Design', 'coding', 'system Testing', 'preliminary Investigation and Analysis'],
        'answer': 'preliminary investigation and Analysis'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'What does the study of an existing system refer to?',
        'options': ['Details of DFD', 'Feasibility Study', 'System Analysis', 'System Planning'],
        'answer': 'System Analysis'
    },
    {
        'question': 'What does RAD stand for?',
        'options': ['Rapid Application Document', 'Rapid Application Development', 'Relative Application Development', 'None of the above'],
        'answer': 'Rapid Application Development'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'The system by which companies are managed and controlled is known as?',
        'options': ['Management', 'Strategic ', 'Corporate', '.Internal'],
        'answer': 'Corporate'
    },
    
    {
        'question': 'Human Resource Management is ?',
        'options': ['Employee oriented', 'Employer oriented', 'Legally oriented', 'None of these'],
        'answer': 'Employer oriented'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'The meaning of the acronym HRM is ?',
        'options': ['Human Relations Management', 'Humanistic Resource Management', 'Human Resource Management', 'Human Resourceful Management'],
        'answer': 'Human Resource Management'
    },

    {
        'question': '______________ are typical solutions to commonly occurring problems in software design.',
        'options': ['Design Problems', 'Design Patterns', 'Design Templates', 'Design Objects'],
        'answer': 'Design Patterns'
    },
    
    {
        'question': 'The concept of patterns was first described by ____________________',
        'options': ['Dennis Ritchie', 'Chistiano Arnaldo', 'Christopher Alexander', 'Chris Allister'],
        'answer': 'Christopher Alexander'
    },
    

    {
        'question': 'What is/are the Elements of design patterns?',
        'options': ['Pattern Name', 'Problem', 'Solution', 'Consequences', 'All the above'],
        'answer': 'All the above'
    },

    {
        'question': 'The book Design Patterns: Elements of Reusable Object-Oriented Software, is popularly known as the "The book by the _________________"',
        'options': ['Gang of Five', 'Gang of Four', 'Group of Four', 'Group of Five'],
        'answer': 'Gang of Four'
    },

    {
        'question': 'Design patterns apply to __________________',
        'options': ['All Programming languages', 'Object-Oriented Programmin Languages', 'Functional Programming languages', 'Procedural Programming languages'],
        'answer': 'Object-Oriented Programmin Languages'
    },

    {
        'question': 'To describe a design pattern, we conider  _____________ sections of the design pattern',
        'options': ['13', '15', '11', '16'],
        'answer': '13'
    },

    {
        'question': 'Design patterns are classified into _______ categories',
        'options': ['three', 'four', 'two', 'five'],
        'answer': 'three'
    },

    {
        'question': 'There are a total of ___________  creational design patterns',
        'options': ['5', '7', '4', '8'],
        'answer': '5'
    },

    {
        'question': 'Operator overloading is an example of ___________ polymorphism',
        'options': ['static', 'dynamic', 'kinetic', 'none'],
        'answer': 'static'
    },

    {
        'question': "'INSERT', 'UPDATE', 'DELETE' are some of the __________ commands",
        'options': ['DDL', 'DCL', 'TCL', 'DML'],
        'answer': 'DML'
    },

    {
        'question': 'In a relational database management system, data is stored in the form of _________________',
        'options': ['Graphs', 'Rows and columns', 'Maps', 'Trees'],
        'answer': 'Rows and columns'
    },
    
    {
        'question': 'In a binary tree, a node has atmost ________ childern',
        'options': ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
        'answer': '2'
    },

    {
        'question': '_______________________ is a collection of homogeneous elements stored in contagious memory locations.',
        'options': ['Tree', 'Graph', 'Array', 'Linked List'],
        'answer': 'Array'
    },

    {
        'question': 'The Output of an AND gate when all the inputs are TRUE is _________',
        'options': ['FALSE', 'TRUE', 'DEPENDS ON OTHER ELEMENTS', 'NONE'],
        'answer': 'TRUE'
    },

    {
        'question': 'Statements in a do-while loop are executed for atleast ________ times',
        'options': ['one', 'two', 'three', 'four'],
        'answer': 'one'
    },

    {
        'question': 'The process of finding useful trends and patterns from huge volumes of data is known as _________________',
        'options': ['Machine learning', 'Data Analytics', 'Data Mining', 'Data Administration'],
        'answer': 'Data Mining'
    },

    {
        'question': 'An instance of a class is known as ___________',
        'options': ['method', 'object', 'constructor', 'interface'],
        'answer': 'object'
    },

    {
        'question': 'Which one of the following is Cloud Platform by Amazon?',
        'options': ['Azure', 'AWS', 'Cloudera', 'All of the mentioned'],
        'answer': 'AWS'

    }, 
    {
        'question': 'Which one of the following options can be considered as the Cloud ?',
        'options': ['Hadoop', 'Intranet', 'Web Applications', 'All of the mentioned'],
        'answer': 'Hadoop'
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which one of the following cloud concepts is related to sharing and pooling the resource ?',
        'options': ['Polymorphism', 'Virtualization', 'Abstraction', 'None of the mentioned'],
        'answer': 'Virtualization'
    }, 
    {
        'question': ' Compromising confidential information comes under _________?',
        'options': [' Bug', 'Threat', ' Vulnerability', 'Attack'],
        'answer': 'Threat'
    },
    {
        'question': ' Lack of access control policy is a __________?',
        'options': ['Bug', 'Threat', 'Vulnerability', 'Attack'],
        'answer': ' Vulnerability'
    }, 
    {
        'question': ' Possible threat to any information cannot be __________ ?',
        'options': [' reduced', 'transferred', 'protected', ' ignored'],
        'answer': ' ignored'
    },
    {
        'question': ' In android application Which file holds to use the internet_____.?',
        'options': [' create file', 'Manifest file', 'system file', 'None of these'],
        'answer': 'Manifest file'
    }, 
    {
        'question': '____ contains the R.java file ?',
        'options': [' src', ' gen', 'Both A and B', '. NOne of these'],
        'answer': ' gen'
    },
    {
        'question': '_____method is used to close an activity ?',
        'options': ['Finish', 'Stop', 'Close', 'None of these'],
        'answer': 'Finish'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'Which of the following is a disadvantage of decision trees??',
        'options': ['Factor analysis', 'Decision trees are robust to outliers', 'Decision trees are prone to be overfit', 'None of the above'],
        'answer': 'Decision trees are prone to be overfit'
    },
    {
        'question': 'Among the following which is not a horn clause? ?',
        'options': ['p → Øq', 'p', 'p → q', 'Øp V q'],
        'answer': 'p → Øq'
    }, 
    {
        'question': ' Different learning methods do not include? ?',
        'options': ['Memorization', 'Analogy', 'Introduction', 'Deduction'],
        'answer': 'Introduction'
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which of the following is considered as the unsolicited commercial email? ?',
        'options': ['Virus', 'Malware', 'Spam', 'All of the above'],
        'answer': 'Spam'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'In ethical hacking and cyber security, there are _______ types of scanning:?',
        'options': ['1', '2', '3', '4'],
        'answer': '3'
    },
    {
        'question': 'Which one of the following is a type of antivirus program?',
        'options': ['Quick heal', 'Mcafee', 'Kaspersky', 'All of the above'],
        'answer': 'All of the above'
    }, 
    {
        'question': ' Which one of the following is actually considered as the first computer virus? ?',
        'options': ['Sasser', 'Blaster', 'Creeper', 'Both A and C'],
        'answer': 'Creeper'
    },
    {
        'question': ' A graph that uses vertical bars to represent data is called a ___',
        'options': ['Bar graph', 'pie graph', 'line graph', 'Scatterplot'],
        'answer': 'Bar graph'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'The process of quantifying data is referred to as __',
        'options': ['Topologyes', 'Digramming', 'Enumeration', 'coding'],
        'answer': 'Enumeration'
    },
    {
        'question': ' ____ are used when you want to visually examine the relationship between two quantitative variables.',
        'options': ['Bar graph', 'pie graph', 'line graph', 'Scatterplot'],
        'answer': 'Scatterplot'
    }, 
    {
        'question': 'Alternative Hypothesis is also called as?',
        'options': ['Composite hypothesis', 'Research Hypothesis', 'Simple Hypothesis', 'Null Hypothesis'],
        'answer': 'Research Hypothesis'
    }
]
